Rishi Bagga

Address: 7 Adrienne avenue, Southall, Middlesex UB1 2QW | Mobile: 07947350277 | Email address: rishi_345@hotmail.co.uk

Personal Statement:

I am currently a final-year undergraduate studying towards a Computer Science degree at City, University of London with industry related experience as a Business Analyst. I have working knowledge of high-level languages and exceptional experience in customer focused roles that require both strategic and problem-solving skills, in preparation for a Technology Consultant role.

Education

2015 – Present City, University of London

Computer Science BSc

This degree is focused on studying the topics of: Programming in Java, Software Engineering, Systems Architecture, Mathematics for Computing, Business Systems, Computation and Reasoning, Professional Development in IT, Data Structures & Algorithms, Object Oriented Analysis Design, Programming in C++, Networks & Operating Systems, Language Processors, Team Project, Human Computer Interaction, Data Mining, E–Commerce, Theory of Computation and Functional Programming and Individual Project.

Projects & Achievements

Certified in CRM, 4tress and T24 - Completed April 2015

Completed a two-player game in Java; Processing. — Completed June 2016. This was completed in my first year of my degree and would relate to this role, as I would contribute towards infrastructure support and maintenance. Developed a movie search mobile application through Android Studio, which facilitated in becoming more confident and proficient in coding. This has also helped me to understand the android operating system more. By the end of this project, I was more confident in approaching complicated problems, not only for myself but also for my peers and colleagues. Developed a website bridging the gap between Tutors and Students where students could find tutors that match their requirements, vice versa. This was essential as it helped me find a solution for thousands of students who require further assistance.

The course also combines practical projects as well as theoretical study, developing both my technical and transferable skills:

- Programming Languages Java, HTML5, CRM, Android Studio, MYSQL, T24, 4TRESS, SPSS
- Analytical and problem-solving skills Proficient problem-solving skills when working alone and with colleagues
 to overcome a complex issue. I am level headed and resilient when identifying issues to overcome the problem
 and acting on an agreed action for me to deliver.
- Written and verbal communication skills As a Customer Assistant and a private Tutor I listen to a range of people to ensure I tailor the solutions to fulfil their needs.
- Team working When working alongside my Google colleagues I motivate and encourage my team members to work harder to reach our target. My people skills bring me together with other users and technology to design and build creative experiences, maintaining positive relationships with clients and colleagues.
- **Time management** Working as a contact centre representative I had many roles, which involved completing tasks quickly and efficiently throughout the day to ensure greater productivity and efficiency.
- Attention to detail I have provided a memorable experience for customers by exceeding their expectations and being zestful. This helps me to plan, organize and prioritise my work, especially when working with sensitive data; this was key to ensure that every transaction was completed securely and efficiently.
- **Presentation skills** Working as a Business Analysis allowed me to record and document each process that was undertaken, complying with regulations put in place to ensure safety and security of sensitive data.

2012 -2014 Greenford Sixth form

A Levels: AA - Business, B - English, C- ICT.

AS Level: C - Politics

2007 – 2012 Dormers Wells High School GCSEs

8 GCSEs including (English, Math's, Science and IT)

Relevant Experience

July 3^{rd,} 2017 – July 28th 2018 Business Analyst Twentieth Century Fox

Provide day to day support across all Fox applications within scope. Receive and log all support calls received by telephone, email or in person. Participate in meetings with the business as required to increase knowledge of business processes, resolve issues and improve the way IT works with the business.

Rishi Bagga

October 2016- December 2018

Sales Demonstrator

Google

Providing exceptional customer service to customers, depicting the uniqueness of Google and its products, i.e. the Google Pixel phone, building rapport and maintaining a professional image. One of the many ways of providing service is to make the customer feel valued, maintaining a zestful attitude whilst having extensive knowledge about the product. This therefore gave me more of a chance to sell the Google device.

Aug 2013 - Aug 2013

Digital Marketing

Arch Agilisys

Working on a project for Godaddy.com to ensure that the correct marketing method attracted the customers attention leading them to purchase the domains and designs of their website. I was in a team managing a project that was given by a large-scale business. I worked in a team and independently presenting my ideas to the group, finding solutions to complex problems, highlighting the factors in order to reach our targets.

Additional Experience

June 2013 - Present

Private Tutor

Tutoring children aged 7-17 English, Math and Science.

June 2015 - Oct 2015

Lettings Negotiator

Stamford's Estate Agent

Ability to communicate verbally with people inside and outside of the organisation, meeting targets by selling and influencing others.

Sept 2014 - April 2015

Contact Centre Representative

Metro Bank

Proficiency with computer software programs, making decisions and solving problems. Completing customer transactions quickly and efficiently, following the security procedures.

April 2014 - Nov 2014

Telephone interviewer

Market Probe Europe

The ability to work in a team structure by making outbound calls to customers for market research purposes, collecting significant data, for example feedback on previously taken out insurances.

Feb 2014 - Feb 2014

Telephone interviewer

Taylor Nelson Sofres

Making outbound calls to customers regarding products they took out previously. One example of this was working on a campaign for Halifax, calling customers up regarding their insurances that they took out.

Sep 2012 – Oct 2013

Tutoring

Kumon

Teaching children in groups of 8-10 from ages 6-16 which involved adapting to the child's understanding and needs personalizing every lesson to the child's capability.

Aug 2012 - May 2014

Tutoring

Aim Educare

Working as a tutor for a tutoring company, I was the teacher of 10 students, teaching them math's, English and science.

March 2011 - March 2013

Customer Assistant

necesver

Provide exceptional service, listen to the customers' individual needs and find a solution that's right. This involved extensive customer service skills, which I had a huge passion for.

Hobbies and Interests

- Great passion in tutoring students on a one to one and group basis. This has been on going for 6 years, enabling me to keep up with the current exams whether that be GCSE or A level.
- Professional Indian drummer playing at weddings, corporate events, birthdays.
- Gym fanatic, running regularly and participating in HIIT training sessions.

References are available upon request.